Joshua Friese

Full-Stack Developer

(919) 622-4805

josh.friese@gmail.com

CONNECT

Young, enthusiastic developer with +1.5 years of experience in demanding corporate and start-up environments.

Eager to perform and detail-oriented with my work, I am proficient at building and maintaining professional relationships and going the extra distance to succeed and satisfy the demands of the craft.

Github

LinkedIn

Portfolio

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Melon Technologies, LLC, Apex, NC — Junior Full-Stack Developer

IANUARY 2018 - MARCH 2018

- Helped develop connections between Python back-end and React.js front-end for the Guardian Angel Platform project.
- Developed optimally performing front-end components for the dashboard of the GAP application using React.js.
- Played an integral role in the planning and modeling phase of the application's lifecycle.

AT&T, Durham, NC — Junior Full-Stack Developer, Apex Systems, LLC

MAY 2017 - JANUARY 2018

- Developed components (using React, Angular, etc) for multiple projects and applications on an enterprise level.
- Tested current applications with Selenium and Jest to improve user experiences.
- Completed two full projects using a Django backend paired with React for third-party companies that have already generated impressive profits for both third-party companies and AT&T
- Took the temporary role of JIRA admin to set up various workflows and scripts using Groovy and Python (in the add-on, ScriptRunner) that automate tasks and listen to events.

SKILLS, TECH & PROFICIENCIES

FRONT-END

HTML/CSS

JavaScript

React.JS

¡Query & Bootstrap

Angular.JS

BACK-END

Git

Python

Django

Jira Administration

Node.JS

mySQL

Ruby

PostgreSQL

TOOLS

Selenium

Docker

REST APIs

RegEx

Agile Methodologies

Groovy

<u>Trilogy Education Services</u>, Raleigh, NC — Teacher's Assistant

AUGUST 2017 - JANUARY 2018

TA for the September 2017 Full-Stack Web Development Course

- Assisted students as they learn advanced concepts of the JavaScript ecosystem and frameworks (like React and Angular).
- Helped students understand the utilization of NoSQL databases and deploying full projects and applications to Firebase.
- Provided excellent guidance to prospective developers (students)
 through grading, code reviews and assistance during office hours.

Masterpeace, The Iron Yard Final Project — Full-Stack Developer

APRIL 2017 - PROJECT STILL IN PROGRESS

A full-scale Django/Vanilla JavaScript web application that integrates an art gallery with social media.

- Shipped and developed web app components using Agile methodologies and Django as a framework.
- Divided tasks by developer and worked collaboratively to deliver a minimum viable product within 3 weeks, splitting the work up in 1 weeks sprints to better organize and gauge performance.
- Investigated new technologies, libraries and processes to create a responsive and comprehensive web application.

EDUCATION

The Iron Yard, Durham, NC — Back-End Engineering

FEBRUARY 2017 - MAY 2017

Accelerated, immersive and fast-paced course encompassing back-end programming. Developed back-end and front-end components of several different projects, not limited to: an implementation of Trello.com, a StackOverflow clone and various command line and web based applications.

<u>Wake Technical Community College</u>, Raleigh, NC — *Computer Engineering Degree*

OCTOBER 2016 - PRESENT

Began the path towards a degree and completed 4 credit hours. Currently working on becoming financially stable and independent before returning to this path. Paired with this degree, I am pursuing a CCNA and Linux Security Specialist certification.